<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on bdwyertech.net</title>
    <link>https://bdwyertech.net/categories/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on bdwyertech.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bdwyertech.net/categories/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switch Security - DHCP Snooping, IP Source Guard and Dynamic ARP Inspection</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2016/03/02/switch-security-dhcp-snooping-ip-source-guard-and-dynamic-arp-inspection-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2016 16:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2016/03/02/switch-security-dhcp-snooping-ip-source-guard-and-dynamic-arp-inspection-2/</guid>
      <description>A few years back, I was designing an Enterprise MDM strategy for iPhone deployments. At some point, I was browsing the Apple Enterprise iOS forum and saw a post about an iOS bug where devices sometimes retain a previously assigned IP (from another network) when joining a new network. In this case, someone was joining a network with a retained IP which coincided with the organization&amp;rsquo;s e-mail server. When this occurred, it apparently disabled e-mail service throughout the organization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitalOcean, Chef and Ohai - Retrieving a Droplet&#39;s Private IP Address</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2015/10/30/digitalocean-chef-and-ohai-retrieving-a-droplets-private-ip-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 21:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2015/10/30/digitalocean-chef-and-ohai-retrieving-a-droplets-private-ip-address/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I attempted to use the Ohai value for node[&#39;cloud_v2&#39;][&#39;local_ipv4&#39;] and node[&#39;cloud&#39;][&#39;local_ipv4&#39;][&#39;ip_address&#39;] to determine the Private IP address of my Cloud-based nodes in a Chef cookbook. Unfortunately, it does not work accurately for DigitalOcean instances any longer.
According to DigitalOcean documentation, if Private Networking is enabled, the IP will be assigned to eth1. Recently, I noticed that a second Private IP address has begun to be assigned to the eth0 interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VLAN Security - VLAN Access Control List&#39;s (VACL)</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/12/09/vlan-security-vlan-access-control-lists-vacl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 02:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/12/09/vlan-security-vlan-access-control-lists-vacl/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying to renew my CCNP as of recently, and I decided to create a refresher blog post about the implementation of VACLs.
VLAN Access Control Lists (VACLs) can be used to implement Access Control at both Layer 2 and Layer 3. Typically, access lists are applied to ingress or egress traffic on a routed, L3 interface. VACL&amp;rsquo;s allow you to apply the filtering to all packets, regardless of direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPDATE: Branch Office Connections – GRE over IPSec VPN</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/11/07/update-branch-office-connections-gre-over-ipsec-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 19:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/11/07/update-branch-office-connections-gre-over-ipsec-vpn/</guid>
      <description>It has been almost 3 years since I wrote Branch Office Connections – GRE over IPSec VPN! For those of you who are familiar with Cisco certification, that means time to renew! Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m coming back now and looking at this lab, I noticed that we are preferring the serial link for traffic! In this day and age, the serial link would likely be the fallback, and a faster, cheaper GRE/IPSEC VPN would likely be the preferable route!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS - Highly-Available NAT in VPC</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/06/16/aws-highly-available-nat-in-vpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2014/06/16/aws-highly-available-nat-in-vpc/</guid>
      <description>Like most sysadmins, one of my primary responsibilities is ensuring high-availability in our environments. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working a lot more with Amazon AWS. Amazon recently began forcing new accounts to make use of VPC. When you create a VPC, an Internet Gateway must be provisioned to route traffic to the Internet. VPC&amp;rsquo;s utilize subnet constructs for virtual networking. Subnets are assigned a routing table, and in the case of a Public subnet, the default route of this table is pointed at the Internet Gateway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branch Office Connections - GRE over IPSec VPN</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/02/25/branch-office-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 22:58:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/02/25/branch-office-connections/</guid>
      <description>While studying for the CCNP Route exam, I noticed that GRE Tunneling and IPSec were mentioned as topics, however configuration of the two was never really covered in the certification guide. In addition, I did not see any labs involving this type of scenario, so I decided to create my own. Hopefully this provides some insight to others about how to configure GRE Tunnels over IPsec. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel bad if this takes you a while, setting up this scenario and writing this up took a whole Saturday afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IP SLA</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/02/20/cisco-ip-sla/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 23:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/02/20/cisco-ip-sla/</guid>
      <description>So while studying for CCNP Route, I came across the concept of IP SLA and utilizing probes to check availability of next-hop addresses prior to instating them inside a route-map. An objective was to have two ISP&amp;rsquo;s listed in a route-map statement, and set all traffic originating from the local router with a next-hop IP of ISP1 as long as it was deemed reachable by the IP SLA tracker probe status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update - Been Busy</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/01/22/update-been-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 20:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/01/22/update-been-busy/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last posted to this blog, so I figured I would post an update. I have been very busy lately working to complete my internship requirements to graduate from college while also studying for the MCITP Enterprise Administrator exam. I should have the latter done in a week or two and will begin studying for the CCNP Route exam.
I have added some new equipment to the lab, including a Dell 4220 42u server rack, Cisco 2821, and another 16gb RAM to my server bringing it to 32gb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOS - show run linenum</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/11/10/cisco-ios-show-run-linenum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 04:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/11/10/cisco-ios-show-run-linenum/</guid>
      <description>So I discovered a nifty little trick recently for Cisco IOS. You can get line numbers to appear alongside your configuration when doing a show run! I found this to be awesome, although I do not think it is available on all IOS since my 3550&amp;rsquo;s running 12.2(44) do not have this feature. My 1841 running the latest 15.1(4) is the device I used to discover it. Rather than doing a simple show run, give show run linenum a shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Switch - ProCurve 1810</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/10/19/network-switch-procurve-1810/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 17:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/10/19/network-switch-procurve-1810/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I decided I would like to acquire a quality, managed switch for my home environment. I wanted something which supported Gigabit Ethernet, Flow Control and Jumbo Frames. These features would complement my Dell PE 2950 ESXi box by providing high performance and future expandability.
At the moment, quality managed gigabit switches are expensive. 10/100 managed switches can easily be acquired on eBay for a decent price, however gigabit models are often seen for upwards of $500 used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell PowerEdge 2950</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/10/dell-poweredge-2950/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2011 20:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/10/dell-poweredge-2950/</guid>
      <description>So recently I decided I wanted a server of my own which I could run VMware ESXi on at home. Previously, my personal &amp;ldquo;server&amp;rdquo; was just an old tower system composed of whatever extra components I had laying around the house. It had a few old hard drives, 4Gb DDR, an Athlon 4000+, and one fan&amp;hellip; Obviously, it has become antiquated, so its time for an upgrade!
While working with server gear in the field, I have found Intel&amp;rsquo;s RMM and HP&amp;rsquo;s iLO Out-of-Band management solutions to be extremely helpful and a technology that I just had to have in my next personal sandbox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware ESXi &amp; Intel SR1550AL Servers</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/02/vmware-esxi-intel-sr1550al-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 12:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/02/vmware-esxi-intel-sr1550al-servers/</guid>
      <description>I recently encountered an issue when running an ESXi 4.1 environment where I was getting a Purple Screen of Death at right about the 24 hour uptime mark. Like most technologists, I first hit Google with the error code and had no luck. I found a similar error code which suggested that it had something to do with a storage I/O issue. The issue did not seem driver related, so I began to look into firmware and BIOS updates for the server.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
