<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tweaks on bdwyertech.net</title>
    <link>https://bdwyertech.net/categories/tweaks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tweaks on bdwyertech.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 16:38:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bdwyertech.net/categories/tweaks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Empty the Active Directory Recycling Bin</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2013/01/22/how-to-empty-the-active-directory-recycling-bin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 16:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2013/01/22/how-to-empty-the-active-directory-recycling-bin/</guid>
      <description>One of the coolest new features in Server 2008 R2 and 2012 is the ability to recover deleted Active Directory objects. Your forest functional level must be at least 2008 R2 in order to activate this feature. Server 2008 R2 introduced the AD Administrative Center which provides a nice GUI to restore deleted objects after activated. However, eventually one might want to permanently empty the contents of this recycling bin. There is no way to do this via the GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Profile Manager – Mountain Lion Migration</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/08/15/apple-profile-manager-mountain-lion-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 21:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2012/08/15/apple-profile-manager-mountain-lion-migration/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had the pleasure of migrating an OSX Lion server to Mountain Lion. It’s primary function was an MDM server for Apple devices. Basically, the upgrade process involves upgrading to Mountain Lion followed by installing the updated Lion Server app.
Primarily, my interactions with the Apple Server have been for Profile Manager functionality. In Lion, the Profile Manager utilized a PostgreSQL backend with a datastore located in /usr/share/devicemgr/backend/. iOS applications and other push to device material were located in the ‘/backend/file_store/’ directory named as their MD5 checksum equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VMware vSphere Client - Clear Recent Connections (RDP Also)</title>
      <link>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/14/vmware-vsphere-client-clear-recent-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 21:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bdwyertech.net/2011/09/14/vmware-vsphere-client-clear-recent-connections/</guid>
      <description>Today I figured out how to empty the recent connections for the VMware vSphere Client. After a while, these begin to add up and I do not like having useless IP addresses and DNS names from experimental ESXi boxes appearing in my client when I attempt to log in. I searched the registry for some no longer functional servers and I found some keys in HKCU which contained the recently connected hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
